Guide to the Orchesis (Stanford University) Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Orchesis (Stanford University) records
1922-1961
SC0140
Orchesis (Stanford University)
5.25 Linear feet (8 boxes)
The collection includes correspondence, programs, photographs and scrapbooks relating to this honorary women's modern dance society.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
The records were received by the Stanford University via administrative transfer from the Women's Athletic Association, Department of Physical Education in 1975, and from Professor Miriam Lidster in 1977.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Orchesis was an honorary modern dance society at Stanford. Members auditioned for election to the society, and had to serve an apprenticeship before receiving full membership.
Description of the Collection
The collection includes the written records of the group beginning in 1936 and extending through 1949, with minimal materials from the 1950s; records include correspondence, minutes, membership lists, programs, and notes including some on their choreography. Also included are photographs, sketches, and scrapbooks covering, sporadically, the years from 1922 to 1961.
Arrangement note
Records are arranged as received.
Access Terms
Orchesis (Stanford University); Modern dance.; Photoprints.
Collection Contents
- Expenditures, descriptions of dances, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Annual budget. November 30, 1938 concert - program, personnel, choreography, personal notes, expenses, critiques, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 1939 May 31 concert: program, choreography, costumes, music, expenses, personal notes, critique (Box 1, Folder 3)
- General correspondence, 1937-1939 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Budget, general correspondence, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Publicity, notes, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Spring concert: personnel, dances, choreography, critiques, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Minutes of meetings, 1939 Sep-1941 Sep (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Budget, membership, constitution, initiation poem, correspondence, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- 1941 Mar studio concert: program, dances, budget, personal note (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Constitution, correspondence, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Apprentice group - personnel, activities, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- May O'Donnell's visit, symposium, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Advertisements of films; comments on photo exhibition, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Critiques of Devi Deja's Bali and Java dancers, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- 1942 Jan 20 concert: choreography, production details (Box 2, Folder 1)
- 1942 Jan 20 concert: publicity invitations, thank you notes (Box 2, Folder 2)
- 1942 Jan 20 concert: critiques and reviews (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Attendance, minutes, activities, pledge, constitution, finances, 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Concerts, programs, correspondence, 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- 1943 Christmas Concert, 1944 Spring Concert, 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Budget, 1946 Spring Concert, correspondence, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Spring Concert, symposium, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- 1948 Spring Concert, annual budget, correspondence, music, 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Budget, programs, spring concert, master lesson, correspondence, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Concert programs, publicity for miscellaneous traveling dance troupes, 1950s (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Programs and history of Annual College Symposia of Northern California, 1937-1961 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Members, 1941 fall (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, general records, 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, minutes, members, 1945-1947 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, minutes, members, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, minutes, members, 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, minutes, members, programs, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Members, miscellaneous notes, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Concerts, 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Minutes, programs, general records, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Programs, 1938-1956 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Photos 12,236 to 12,258: action shots outdoors, individual and group portraits, and one showing the photographers, 1945-1946 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Photos 12,259 to 12,272: action shots outdoors, individual and group portraits, 1945-46, and one indoor shot of Jacqueline Ogg, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Photos 12,273 to 12,293: dancers on stage and two outdoor action shots, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Photos 12,294 to 12,307: dancers from Spring Concert 1947 and other dancers on stage, 1948-1949 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Photos 12,308 to 12,324: dancers on stage and outdoors, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Photos 12,324 to 12,332: dancers on stage and outdoors, 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Photos 12,333 to 12,343: dancers outdoors and two shots on stage, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Photos 12,344 to 12,358: dancers at Frost Amphitheater, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Photos 12,359 to 12,375: dancers on stage and outdoors, 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Photos, mostly outdoors, 1947 spring (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Photos, May Fete, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Photos in Frost Amphitheater, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Photos, 1957, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Photos, 1945, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Photos by Dan C. Baker, on stage, 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Photos by Dan C. Baker, outside, 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Photos by Dan C. Baker, Jo Haskell, accompanist (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Photos, outside (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Photo, stage performance (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Photos by Overstreet, "Fall of the City" and "Pied Piper", 1957 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Photos by Overstreet, unidentified, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 4-6)
- Posters (2) (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Scrapbook: clippings, photographs, programs, club records, etc., 1933-1953 (Box 6)
- Mounted image by Dan C. Baker, "Primitive" (Box 7)
- Scrapbook: clippings, photographs, programs, club records, etc., 1954-1960 (Box 7)
- Six cartoon-type drawings of dancers by "her" (Box 8)
- Nine charcoal sketches by Portia (3), Woodham (2), and unsigned (4) (Box 8)
- Eight mounted photographs by Gilbert Finlay, circa 1941 (Box 8)